Julian Beard

Full-Stack Software Engineer

(517) 626.4000 · julian.beard93@gmail.com · julianbeard.codes · in/julian-a-beard · github.com/badjab326

Southern California based Full-Stack Software Engineer with nearly two years in various team-based agile software development projects, and an extensive repertoire of communication, team building and resource management skills.

SKILLS

Languages - TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - Angular, React, Node.js, Express.js, Django Database - MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose | Other - Angular Material, ChakraUI, REST, AWS S3, Postman

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Idoona, Full-Stack Software Engineer | Bremen, Germany

Sep. 2022 - Present

- Plan architecture for new software projects, determining appropriate tech stack and MVP outline.
- Utilize agile workspace to collaborate with each member of the team and ensure quality output.
- Use Mongo, Express, React, Node (MERN) and PayloadCMS/TypeScript to build and maintain client scale applications.
- Research and demo new frameworks to leadership for integration.
- Engineer user-focused survey tool making use of Government supplied data.

Dreamcatch, Full-Stack Software Engineer (Contract) | Atlanta, GA

April 2023 - Present

- Scaffolded multiple applications to customer's technology and product requirements.
- Made use of Angular framework and Angular Material component library to quickly bring projects off the ground.
- Implemented Node and MySQL backends on hosted versioned environments.
- Leveraged flexbox, media queries and Angular Material grid list to design interfaces universally across devices.
- Used strong communication and team management skills to work with highly diverse groups of clients.

PERSONAL SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

2022 - Present

Black In Gaming

- Built from the ground up using Angular, TypeScript, Angular Material, Node and PayloadCMS.
- Utilizes Node.js backend and PayloadCMS admin panel to manage and serve detailed information on black video game characters.
- Custom components built using Angular Material and designed with mobile browsers in mind via responsive design.

Avatar Yearbook

- Worked as Lead Backend Dev on a multi-page, create, read, update, delete (CRUD) digital yearbook for bootcamp graduates
- Used React.js to serve the front-end with Javascript methods and functions.
- Worked with an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend leveraging restful design, all CRUD operations, and testing with Postman.
- Served the backend of the application using Express methods and functions utilizing MongoDB database management.
- Added Backend user authentication/authorization using Google Firebase.

Gym Planner

- Produced app designed to give users the ability to digitally plan, track and optimize their workouts.
- Constructed with Python, Django, Materialize CSS and PostgreSQL.
- Implemented full user authentication and authorization, as well as admin functionality.
- Modeled with MVT architecture, managed deployment pipeline with use of Heroku.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

April 2022 - July 2022

Completed an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies, including development of multiple individual and group projects.

COURSERA | REMOTE

Meta Full-Stack Engineering

July 2022 - Oct 2022

Certified in multiple Software Engineering courses offered and sponsored by Meta:

- Introduction to Front-End Development
- HTML and CSS in depth
- Programming with JavaScript
- React Basics

- Introduction to Back-End Development
- Version Control
- Programming in Python